<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>programmers-limbo on Pavel Danov / 亶保罗</title><link>https://underscorehao.net/categories/programmers-limbo/</link><description>Recent content in programmers-limbo on Pavel Danov / 亶保罗</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 12:28:22 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://underscorehao.net/categories/programmers-limbo/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>On Consultancies</title><link>https://underscorehao.net/programmers-limbo/on-consultancies/</link><pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2023 12:28:22 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://underscorehao.net/programmers-limbo/on-consultancies/</guid><description>Table of contents Introduction What to look for in a consultancy Life at a consultancy On the bench The problems you&amp;rsquo;ll face (that you might not care about&amp;hellip; but you should) Career progression TL; DR Introduction There are millions of consultancies out there and more are popping left and right by the minute. Some are outsource shops or a couple of dev friends teaming up in trying to create a business, others are big multinational corporations that bid on big government or enterprise contracts.</description></item><item><title>Programmer's Limbo - Lessons learned from life in software development</title><link>https://underscorehao.net/programmers-limbo/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Apr 2023 22:34:30 +0100</pubDate><guid>https://underscorehao.net/programmers-limbo/</guid><description>In this series I will share some of the lessons I&amp;rsquo;ve learned throughout my software development career. Some of them might be targeted to people that are not in the industry, but want or are about to get into it. Others will be useful to more experienced people with a position or two (or more) under the belt.
It should be noted that everything described here is derived from my own experiences.</description></item></channel></rss>