<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>life on Pavel Danov</title>
    <link>https://underscorehao.net/tags/life/</link>
    <description>Recent content in life on Pavel Danov</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 13:00:00 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://underscorehao.net/tags/life/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>New Year, New Process</title>
      <link>https://underscorehao.net/2022/04/new-year-new-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 13:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://underscorehao.net/2022/04/new-year-new-process/</guid>
      <description>At the start of 2022 I decided to start journaling. I&amp;rsquo;ve tried both digital and physical approaches in the past, but neither stuck. It might&amp;rsquo;ve been due to my mindset at the time, but I&amp;rsquo;ve found the best option for me now is an actual physical notebook. Total shocker I know - using dead trees for my own nefarious purposes. Might be a relic of my school days, but my thought flows better on paper despite 20 years of constant PC use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2021 Book List</title>
      <link>https://underscorehao.net/2021/11/2021-book-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 20:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://underscorehao.net/2021/11/2021-book-list/</guid>
      <description>Here I&amp;rsquo;ll be adding books I&amp;rsquo;m currently reading and have read during the year. Usually I read more than one book at the same time. I make a distinction between recreational reading and doing so as part of something I&amp;rsquo;m currently studying. If I&amp;rsquo;m studying from a book I also take notes, pay extra attention etc.
Currently Reading    Name Author(s)     C++ Primer (5th Edition) Stanley B.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In the Pursuit of Knowledge and Mastery</title>
      <link>https://underscorehao.net/2021/09/in-the-pursuit-of-knowledge-and-mastery/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2021 21:30:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://underscorehao.net/2021/09/in-the-pursuit-of-knowledge-and-mastery/</guid>
      <description>The Pursuit Last year has been interesting on a multitude of levels. Global pandemic and economic doom notwithstanding, COVID has been a net positive for me on a professional and financial level.
With that said earlier this year while in lockdown I arrived at the conclusion that I have more or less plateaued as far as my skills and knowledge are concerned. It&amp;rsquo;s not something I like to admit, but after asking myself questions around what I&amp;rsquo;ve actually learned I wasn&amp;rsquo;t satisfied with the answers.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
